Thomas Mann Collection, 1881-1971: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
Thomas Mann Collection
1881-1971
C0295
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
6.1 linear feet 13 boxes
Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955.
Consists of letters, manuscripts, photographs, and other materials from Nobel Prize winning author Thomas Mann, given by Caroline Newton, and also of those collected by Princeton University Library with funds provided by Caroline Newton.
Caroline Newton was a psychoanalyst, once a student of Freud in Vienna. Newton gave generously to Princeton of her books as well as her manuscripts. She was the daughter of the well-known collector A. Edward Newton. The Thomas Mann Collection consists of letters, manuscripts, photographs, and other materials given by Caroline Newton, and also of those collected by Princeton University Library with funds provided by Caroline Newton.
Thomas Mann, brother of Heinrich Mann, was an author of novels, plays, and essays. He won the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1929, fled Germany and came to the U.S. (to Princeton) in 1938, and became a citizen in 1944. Among his best-known works (in English translation) are Buddenbrooks (1901), Death in Venice (1912), and The Magic Mountain (1924). Other publications by Mann include The Holy Sinner (New York: Knopf, 1951), Die Betrogene (Frankfurt am Main: Fischer, 1953), Der Erwahlte (Frankfurt am Main: Fischer, 1967).
Caroline Newton first met Thomas Mann in Berlin in 1929. When he had to leave Germany in 1937, she offered him her house in Jamestown, Rhode Island, and then she helped the Manns establish their home at 65 Stockton Street, Princeton, New Jersey, in 1938. By then Mann was a major German novelist, winner of the 1929 Nobel Prize for Literature, and author of Buddenbrooks. He wrote Lotte in Weimar and began Joseph The Provider while in Princeton. He died August 12, 1955. Caroline Newton arranged for two Mann commemorations at Princeton in 1964 and 1970. Newton died January 20, 1975 at age 82.
The collection contains works of Mann including lectures, addresses, radio broadcasts (1942-1943), proofs for Der Erwahlte and a chapter of Lotte in Weimar, and a facsimile of Die Betrogene, as well as correspondence between Mann and many German and American intellectuals, such as Charles Neider, Arthur Hubscher, Hans Hulsen, Erich von Kahler, and Caroline Newton. In addition, there are memorabilia, photographs of Mann and several friends (Arturo Toscanini, Bruno Walter, etc.), and printed matter relating to Mann, as well as articles and essays of which he is the subject.
Collection is open for research use.
Most of the collection was given to the Library by Caroline Newton and added to with funds she provided. A student of Freud in Vienna, Newton first met Mann in 1929, and later helped the Manns establish their home in Princeton in 1938.
Related collection: Caroline Newton Papers (C0517)
The Letters of Thomas Mann to Caroline Newton were printed by Princeton University Library in 1971, with English translation of all 57 letters (1937-1955). A selection of Mann correspondence is printed in Thomas Mann Briefe, S. Fischer Verlag, 1961-1965, 3 volumes, and references are given in this List (call number 3471.73.3185 and EX). Thomas Mann's letters to Caroline Newton are in the Thomas Mann Collection, but letters to her from other members of the Mann family are in the Caroline Newton Papers (C0517).
Newton, Caroline, 1893-, collector.; German fiction -- 20th century.; Exiles' writings -- 20th century.; Novelists, German -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Galley Proofs (Printing) -- 20th century.; Lectures.; Photographic prints.; Radio scripts.; European literature
- Series 1: Works, 1915 May-1959 February 8; 14 folders
  Consists of the works of Thomas Mann, primarily addresses and lectures.
  Not arranged according to any arrangement scheme.
  - Address: To American guild for German Cultural Freedom, New York, 1937 April 20 (xerox of typescript, in English), portion of 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Address: To World Congress of Writers, 1939 May 9 (xerox of typescript, in English), portion of 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Address: "Dear Friends, Allow me to use this form of address. It is inspired by the words in which you characterise the meaning and purpose of your Congress..." (Translated by Barthold Fles. photocopy of typescript, n.d.), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Address to Princeton University Convocation, upon receiving honorary degree of Doctor of Letters, 1939 May 18Original manuscript in German with typescript of English translation, 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - "Die Bertrogene." Facsimile (no. 171) of original AMs, 91 pp., 1953; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Der Erwählte. Boxed page-proofs, 323 pp., 1951; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Letter to "Svenska Dagbladet," TMsS with holograph corrections, 13 pp., Stockholm, 1915 May; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - "Die Lager" (statement on concentration camps), TMs (carbon), 1945Corrected typescript, 3 pp., and telegraphic version sent to Charles Neider, 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Autobiographical lecture (in English), TMs (carbon) with holograph correction, 34 pp. n.d., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - "From Childhood Play to Death in Venice" (lecture), TMs (carbon) with holograph corrections, 19pp., Princeton, 1940; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Lecture (in German) on Der Zauberberg, TMs (carbon) with holograph corrections, 16 pp., Princeton, May 1939 and TMs (carbon) with holograph corrections, 17 pp., Princeton, 1939 May; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Lotte in Weimar. Galley proofs of Chapter 5, 1938 April 19. (16 galleys), 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - "My relation to psychoanalysis," (essay), TMs (carbon) with holograph corrections, 2 pp., 1926; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - "Lübeck," transcript of radio broadcast (April 12, 1942) by European Service of the BBC, TMsS (carbon) with holograph corrections, 1942(includes transcript of English translation), 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - "America talks to Australia," transcript of radio broadcast, AMs, 3pp., 1943 February 2 (in German), 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Statement on the German occupation of Austria taken during an interview with Albert Hubbell, TMs with holograph corrections, 3 pp., New York, February 1939 (?). Includes explanatory letter from Albert Hubbell to Charles Neider, January 29, 1959 and Neider's reply, 1959 February 8; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Series 2: Letters from Thomas Mann, 1901-1975; 3 boxes (1 partial)
  Consists of letters written by Thomas Mann to individuals such as Félix Bertaux, Paul Nikolaus Cossmann, and Caroline Newton, as well as others.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Paul Bekker (1882-1937) musicologist. 1 letter, Munich, 1925 September 1; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Madame Celine Bertaux, 1 letter, 1948 October 19 ( Briefe), 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Félix Bertaux (1881-1948), French translator and critic. 63 letters and postcards, 1923-1948 (4 published in Briefe), 5 folders (Folder 3-7)
  - Hans Block. 1 letter, Paris, 1926 January 24; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Ida Boy-Ed (1852-1928) novelist. 1 letter, 1922 December 5 ( Briefe), 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Julian P. Boyd. 1 letter, 1942 September 26; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Anna Brenner. 1 letter, 1947 May 4; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Joseph Chapiro (José) (1893-1962). 1 letter and 11 cards, 1912-1928; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Paul Nikolaus Cossmann (1869-1941). 11 letters and 11 cards, 1912-1928; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Edward Cushing. 2 letters, 1938-1939. Regarding aid to Genia Schwarzwald (1940), an Austrian educator, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - J. R. de la Torre Bueno. 1 letter, 1941 September 7; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Dr. Arthur Elösser (1870-1937). 4 cards, 1920-1937; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Fritz Endress (1886-1945), journalist. 11 letters and 9 cards, 1918-1930 (5 published in Briefe), 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Edward Engel. 1 letter, Munich, 1920 December 2; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Ludwig Ewers (1870-1946). 1 letter and 1 card, Munich, 1910-1922; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Dr. Hans Feist (1887-1952), translator. 6 letters, 1946-1949. (1 published in Briefe), 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Hedwig Fischer (Mrs. Samuel Fischer) (1871-1952). 1 letter, 1935 June 8; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Samuel Fischer (1859-1934), publisher. 8 letters and 4 transcripts, 1903-1924; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Alexander M. Frey (1881-1957), author. 50 letters, 7 cards, and 1 telegram, 1929-1954 (10 published in Briefe), 4 folders (Folder 23-26)
  - Herr Frisch. 2 letters, 1947 and 1949, 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - William D. Geer. 1 letter, n.d., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Herr Gottlieb. 1 letter, 1936 January 3; 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - Dr. Hahne. 2 letters, 1951; 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Dr. Ernst Hanhart. 3 letters, 15 cards, 1921-1936; 1 folder (Folder 31)
  - Herr Hannecher. 1 letter, Munich, 1916 January 6; 1 folder (Folder 32)
  - Rudolf Heidler. 1 letter, Munich, 1915 October 15; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - Dr. Carl Heine, theatre director. 1 letter, 1907 March 12 (published?), 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - Herr Himminghoffer. 1 letter, Munich, 1930 June 23; 1 folder (Folder 35)
  - Ludwig von Hofman (1861-1945). 1 card, 1931 August 16; 1 folder (Folder 36)
  - Karl Hönn (1883-). 3 letters, 1916-1925; 1 folder (Folder 37)
  - Dr. Arthur Hübscher (1899-), editor of Suddeutsche Monatshifte. 1.) 4 letters, 1926-1928; 2.) "Antwort an Arthur Hübscher" (corrected typescript and galley proof); 3.) 20 letters to Hübscher from various people about Thomas Mann's "Betrachtungen eines Unpolitischen,", 4 folders (Folder 38-41)
  - Hans von Hülsen (1890-), critic and Hauptmann biographer. 54 letters and 48 cards, 1908-1934 (with typed transcriptions), 7 folders (Folder 42-48)
  - George B. de Huszar. 2 letters, 1945; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Herr Isaac. 1 letter, 1946 August 31 (with author's corrections), 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Arnold Eugene Jenny. 1 letter in English, 1945 September 18; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Charles H. Jordan. 1 letter, Tulsa, 1938 March 18 (with English translation in pencil), 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Antoinette von Kahler. 3 letters, 1940-1947; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Erich von Kahler (1885-1970). 55 letters and 2 cards, 1931-1955 (these have all been published, in German and in English; translation in An Exceptional Friendship, ), 1975; 4 folders (Folder 6-9)
  - Dr. Alfred Kantorowicz. 5 letters, 1943-1954; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Robert Klein. 1 letter, Princeton, 1940 December 4; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Herr Klöber. 1 letter, 1951 April 9; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Max Krell. 2 letters, Munich, 1915 and 1919, 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Herr Ludwig. 1 letter, 1950 March 5; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Professor John H. H. Lyon. 1 letter (in English), Princeton, 1940 October 30; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Nellie (Mrs. Viktor) Mann (1895-1962). 2 letters, 1949 (published in Briefe), 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Viktor Mann (1890-1949), Mann's brother. 19 letters, 1945-1947. (8 published in Briefe), 2 folders (Folder 17-18)
  - Hans Mühlestein (1887-), art Historian and translator. 9 letters and 1 card, 1913-1952; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Charles Neider (1915-), author and editor. 51 letters, 1939-1954. Includes 2 telegrams regarding Neider's book Stature of Thomas Mann, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Caroline Newton (1893-1975). 56 letters, 3 cards, and 4 telegrams, 1937-1955 (with notes by Caroline Newton attached to the last 2 Mann letters to her). All are privately printed in German and in English translation, Princeton, 1971 (10 published in Briefe), 5 folders (Folder 21-25)
  - Walter H. Perl (1909-). 17 letters and 1 card (1 published in Briefe), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - George M. Priest, Professor at Princeton University. 7 letters, 1939-1941 (1 in English), 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Dr. Paul Raché, Hamburg critic. 2 letters, 1902-1931; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Hans Reisiger (1884-1968), author and translator. 10 letters and 3 cards, 1925-1953 (2 published in Briefe), 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - George Martin Richter. 17 letters and 38 cards, 1901-1926; 5 folders (Folder 1-5)
  - Gigi Richter, Mann's godchild. 1 card, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Dr. David Riesmann (1909-). 1 letter in English, 1940; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Carl F. Riter. 2 letters in English, 1939; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Roger Senhouse. 2 letters and 1 card, 1946-1955; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Shaffer, 1922 March 28; 1 folder (Folder 9a)
  - Roger Gregor Smith. 1 letter in English, n. d., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Agnes Speyer-Ulmann. 9 letters and 10 cards (1 published in Briefe), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Dr. Steiner. 1 letter, St. Moritz, 1950 August 2; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Dr. Hudson Strode. 1 letter in English, 1941 February 15; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - George Sylvester Viereck, American journalist. 1 letter, Munich, 1928 March 13; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Bruno Walter (1876-1962), editor. 2 letters, 1933; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Hans von Weber (1872-1924), editor. 1 letter and 2 cards, 1913-1918; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Wolfgang von Weber. 1 letter, 1924 October 17; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Dr. Widmer. 1 letter, Kusnacht, 1935 April 22 (letter regards Erich von Kahler), 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Friderike Zweig (1882-). 1 letter, 1942 (letter regards the suicide of Stefan Zweig), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Unidentified recipients. 19 letters and 1 card, 1902-1930; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Unidentified "Verehrte Frau." 1 letter, Stockholm, 1949 May 28; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Unidentified publisher. 1 letter, Erlenbach, 1953 November 18 (letter regards Frau Lennartz "Die Dichter unserer Zeit"), 1 folder (Folder 22)
- Series 3: Letters to Thomas Mann, 1911-1954; 5 folders
  Consists of letters received by Thomas Mann from Paul Nikolas Cossmann, Alexander M. Frey, Hans von Hülsen, Graf Hermann Keyserling, and Charles Neider.
  - Paul Nikolas Cossmann (1869-1941), editor of Suddeutschen Monatshefte. 11 letters, 1911-1921; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Alexander M. Frey (1881-1957), author. 13 letters, 1934-1954; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Hans von Hülsen (1890-), author and journalist. 3 letters, 1924-1929; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Graf Hermann Keyserling (1880-1946), historian. 1 letter, 1919; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Charles Neider (1915-), author and journalist. 27 letters and 3 telegrams (copies), 1940-1953; 1 folder (Folder 27)
- Series 4: Correspondence of Others, 1911-1964 October 23; 8 folders
  Consists of the correspondence of others, including Heinrich Mann, Katja (Pringsheim) Mann, Klaus Mann, Monika Mann, and Charles Neider.
  - Heinrich Mann (1872-1950). 2 letters and 2 cards to Agnes Speyer-Ulmann, 1911-1912; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Katja (Pringsheim) Mann. 7 letters in English, 1946-1955 to Charles Neider. 1 printed card and one reply from Neider to Mrs. Mann, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - Katja (Pringsheim) Mann. 1 telegram, 1964 October 23 to Princeton University, 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Klaus Mann (1906-1949). Correspondence with Charles Neider. 17 letters in English from Klaus to Neider and 4 letters in English from Neider to Klaus, 1942-1946; 1 folder (Folder 31)
  - Monika Mann (1910-). Correspondence with Charles and Vivian Neider. 15 letters and 4 cards in English from Monika to Neider and 2 letter in English from Neider to Monika, 1947-1954; 1 folder (Folder 32)
  - Charles Neider (1915-). Correspondence with various writers an scholars soliciting contributions to his anthology The Stature of Thomas Mann, 1947. (57 letters dated 1946). Letters to Neider: Conrad Aiken, 2; W. H. Auden, 2; Joseph Warren Beach, 2; Hermann Broch, 4; Pearl S. Buck; Kenneth Burke; Willa Cather; Cyril Connolly; David Daiches; Lion Feuchtwanger; Frederic Fischer; André Gide (signed by secretary); Martin Gumpert; Henry Hatfield, 2; Aldous Huxley; Christopher Isherwood; Charles Jackson, 2; F. R. Leavis; Harry Levin, 3; Ludwig Lewisohn, 2; Robert Morse Lovell, 2; E. A. Lowe; Helen Tracy (Porter) Lowe, 2; Heinrich Mann; F. O. Mathiessen; H. L. Mencken, 2; Gabriela Mistral, 2; Lewis Mumford, 2; Alfred Neumann, 2; J. B. Priestley, 2 (signed by secretary); Eleanor Roosevelt, Arnold Schoenberg; Bernard Shaw; Lionel Trilling; Bruno Walter; Glenway Wescott; Hermann J. Weigand, Frank Lloyd Wright (signed by secretary); Sigrid Undset, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - Charles Neider. 4 letters from Thomas Mann's secretary, 1939-1947; 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - Charles Neider. Envelopes (11) written by Mann and 3 lists, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 35)
- Series 5: Photocopies and Photostats of Correspondence of Others, 1939-1969; 3 boxes (1 partial)
  Consists of photocopies and photostats of correspondence of others, including Félix Bertaux, Erich von Kahler, Caroline Newton, and Charles Neider, as well as others.
  - Bertaux, Félix, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Chapiro, Joseph (José), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Fischer, Samuel, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Fles, Barthold, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Frey, Alexander, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Frey to Mann (originals in box 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Hanhart, Ernst, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Hülsen, Hans von, dates not examined; 2 folders (Folder 8-9)
  - Hülsen to Mann (originals in box 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Kahler, Erich von, dates not examined; 2 folders (Folder 11-12)
  - Mann, Viktor, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Mather, Frank Jewett, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified, dates not examined; 3 folders (Folder 3-5)
  - Mühlestein, Hans, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Newton, Caroline, dates not examined; 2 folders (Folder 7-8)
  - Perl, Walter H., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Priest, George M., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Reisiger, Hans, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Richter, George Martin, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Weber, Hans von, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Fles, Barthold to Albert Einstein, 1939 and to Erich von Kahler, 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Mann, Katharine (Katja). 25 letters to Erich and Mrs. Kahler, 1940-1969; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Mann, Klaus (1906-1949) to Charles Neider, 1942-1949; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Mann, Monika (1910-) to Charles and Vivian Neider, 1947-1954; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Neider, Charles (1915-) to Thomas and Katja Mann, 1939-1955; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Neider, Charles (1915-) to various authors and scholars, 1946 (regarding The Stature of Thomas Mann; originals in Box 4, Folder 33), 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Series 6: Thomas Mann as Subject, 1913 February 13-1988 March; 17 folders
  Consists of works with Thomas Mann as subject from authors such as Andreas Dorpalen, Herbert Lehnert, and Mark Van Doren, as well as others.
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Dorpalen, Andreas. 2 essays: "Germany: 1871-1890," 12 pp. and "Germany: 1890-1918," 25 pp. Quotes Thomas Mann especially his "Betrachtungen eines Unpolitischen", dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Hallgarten, Wolfgang. "My Recollections of Thomas Mann and his Family's Life in Europe," TMs, 29 pp. with plan of neighborhood in Munich, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Hülsen, Hans von (1890-). "Die Bruder Mann," TMs (photocopy) with holograph corrections by Thomas Mann, 4 pp., 1913 February 13; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Jonas, Klaus W., Dr. (Professor at University of Pittsburgh). 2 articles: "Thomas Mann Collections," 14 pp. and "Thomas Mann und Amerika," 8 pp., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Kahler, Erich V. (1885-1970), historian. 4 articles: "Sakularisiering des Teufels," AMs (in pencil), 34 pp., 1948; "Thomas Mann's Dr. Faustus" (offprint from Commentary, April 1949); "Die Erwahlten" ( Die Neue Rundschau, 1955), TMs, 18 pp.; "Gedenkrede auf Thomas Mann" ( Die Neue Randschau 1956), AMs, 35 pp., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Lange, Viktor, Professor. Address delivered October 24, 1964 at unveiling of tablet on 65 Stockton Street, Princeton, N. J., TMs with holograph corrections, 3 pp., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Lange, Viktor, Professor. "Thomas Mann as a Critic of his Age," TMs (carbon), 21 pp., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Lehnert, Herbert (Rice University). "Thomas Mann in Exile, 1933-1938," TMs, 32 pp. and 14 pp. of footnotes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Lehnert, Herbert (Rice University). "Thomas Mann in Princeton," TMs, 31 pp. and 10 pp. of footnotes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Pringsheim, Klaus H. "Thomas Mann in America: Some Political Comments," TMs, 17 pp. (lecture given at Columbia, Missouri, February 15, 1962), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Thiemer, Horst. Typescript of radio talk, Documentation of Deutschland Funk, 4/1/1971, "Thomas Mann in Princeton," TMs, 14 pp. (in German), with remarks of V. Lange, H. Leynert, and Mrs. V. Kahler, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Van Doren, Mark (1894-1972). "Joseph and His Brothers," TMs (carbon), 21 pp. with cover letter, October 31, 1956 (lecture given at Bryn Mawr on October 5, 1958), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Zucker Kandl, Victor, professor and musicologist. "Thomas Mann, the Musician," an address delivered October 24, 1964 at unveiling of tablet on 65 Stockton Street, Princeton, N. J., TMs (carbon), 12 pp., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Memorabilia and Souvenirs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous lists, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Agnes Speyer-Ulmann. "Heinrich Mann," AMsS, 2 pp., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Papers from a Mann symposium at University of California, Irvine, 1988 March; 1 folder (Folder 23)
- Series 7: Photographs and Pictures, 1881-1960; 2 boxes (1 partial)
  Consists of photographs and pictures of Thomas Mann, Katja Mann, and various locations.
  Arranged by subject of photograph.
  - Thomas Mann, 3 photographs, 1881-1899; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Thomas Mann, 5 photographs, 1925-1930s (photograph dated 12/23/29 has autographed notes), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Thomas Mann, 12 photographs, 1940s-1950s; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Thomas Mann, 1 photograph, award of honorary doctorate, Oxford, 1949 May 13; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Thomas Mann with poodle, 1 photograph, inscription to Caroline Newton, 1952; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Thomas Mann, 12 photographs, 1955; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Thomas Mann, 6 photographs, Kilchberg, Switzerland, 1955; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Thomas Mann, 2 photographs, delivering Schiller address, 1955; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Thomas and Katja Mann, 7 photographs, 1930-1955; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Thomas Mann Family, 9 photographs, 1909-1950; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Thomas and Katja Mann with group, 1 photograph, circa 1906; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Thomas Mann with grandchildren, 4 photographs, 1941-1947; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Thomas Mann with Harold W. Dodds, 1 photographs, Princeton, 1939 May 18; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Thomas Mann with Dorothy Thompson, 1 photograph, New York, 1938 May; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Thomas Mann with Arturo Toscanini and Bruno Walter, 2 photographs, Salzburg, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Thomas Mann at a reception for Alvin Johnson (educator), 3 photographs with booklet to A. Johnson (introduction by Mann), Philadelphia, 1943 November 27; 1 folder (Folder 16)